<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-20T10:55:55+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LavaLens - Playground for Octavian Aarden</title><subtitle>Movie reviews with a focus on European film. Stories and toughts are also included.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Le Week-end (2013) – 3.5/5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Le-Week-end-(2013)" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Le Week-end (2013) – 3.5/5" /><published>2021-02-20T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Le-Week-end-(2013)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Le-Week-end-(2013)">&lt;p&gt;This British-French movie takes us on a journey in Paris alongside an ageing British couple that try to rekindle their relationship with a weekend getaway in the city of love for their 30th anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning we can see that they view this trip with different eyes, Nick, the philosophy professor wants to please his wife and bring some passion back, while Meg is looking for adventures, either by herself or together if there is no other way. Lead by Meg they wander the streets looking for good food and drink until they find a proper restaurant to enjoy. Along the whole weekend she is not shy to express that this marriage is like a cage for her and the idea of breaking free from it and from the norm of her life and family is something that has had on her mind for a long time. All this happens while Nick admits to being forced to retire from his university and showing his need for the comfort of his family, his wife and their needy adult child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of an ageing couple that approaches retirement is not new, especially with highly educated upper middle class intellectuals that go through the pains of not having done anything remarkable in the past decades. In this movie it boils down to the different perspectives the main characters have for the future, the wife thinking about breaking out of the cocoon while the husband is looking at making it even more comfortable albeit tighter and with less freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midway during the film, Morgan, an old friend and mentee of Nick’s makes an appearance. Morgan is everything they both lack in their life: charismatic, successful and loved, he seems to be what Nick might have been if life had gone a bit more according to wishes, while Meg loves his spontaneity and adventurous side that does not adhere to most norms, having for example a young pregnant new wife. This character brings the couple to a boiling point but it also is their last hope when they remain without money, thus ending the movie in a metaphor of showing them what they lack and hate in each other but also giving hope to their relationship and to being able to borrow some money for their tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing to complain about the acting, both actors give solid performances and the cinematography is also great, it gives us enough of Paris to get a great European city vibe but it does not go over board in making it the main character of the movie and all this happens with great jazz background music. Although the ending brings a happy feeling to the viewer, I feel it lacked a bit in a more consistent conclusion, the characters being not far off in the ending from the beginning, just with an adventure in their bags and a reassurance of what the relationship really is, and also was for the last 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="drama" /><summary type="html">This British-French movie takes us on a journey in Paris alongside an ageing British couple that try to rekindle their relationship with a weekend getaway in the city of love for their 30th anniversary.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2021/02/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2021-02-20T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2021/02/20/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2021/02/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>