<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-20T21:10:49+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LavaLens - writing playground</title><subtitle>I have gained an increasing interest in storytelling in recent years. Movies, novels and even poetry fuel my imagination with the potential they have to influence others. No other medium is a close to translating toughts from one person to another as the written word and more recently the moving pictures. I write movie reviews with a focus on European film, short stories and toughts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Life gamification</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Life-gamification" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life gamification" /><published>2021-02-20T20:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T20:11:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Life-gamification</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Life-gamification">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_03_gaming-on-mobile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gaming on mobile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never a hardcore gamer. I have played a little chess competitively as a teen and I really enjoyed playing WW2 shooters like Call of Duty 2, and football games like Fifa and Pro Evolution Soccer with friends. In my twenties I also played Football Manager, but I never got into the over night binge gaming negative stereotype that the press likes to throw around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my job has gotten increasingly stressful since Coronavirus started, and the divide between work life and personal time has all but disappeared, I found that I have trouble thinking about something that is not related to my job if I do not find a way to disconnect in a more blunt fashion after my work hours. With gyms still being closed in the Netherlands, I purchased an Nvidia Shield and a game controller to get into gaming again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to tell you that it works. Half an hour of gaming after closing my work laptop has the ability to really disconnect me from the previous 8-10 hours. What I also see in gaming after almost a decade of not playing has made me think the concept of gamification. As humans we are incredibly competitive, as a side effect of evolution. We want to win, we want to prove that we are better than others. Champions are popular and being a champion in your field might, on a primal level, increase your chances of procreating, if I am allowed to bring the discussion to an animalistic instinct level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What games have managed to capture in an incredibly efficient way, is our need to become better, our need to progress and our need to best others. Games are addicting for a reason, it let’s you see the progress you make immediately. We all know that going to the gym is good for us, but as the results cannot be seen in a short feedback loop, it is not as addictive to improve in that way as it is to go from level 4 to level 6 in Rocket League. This short essay has a long introduction but the main point here is the ability of gaming and game related activities to tap into a primal need as human beings. What we need to do now, as a society, is to translate those short feedback loops into real life skills. Games are fun, but gamifying medical school (6 years) or gym results (&amp;gt;1 year) is something that might push us to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-current-gaming-setup&quot;&gt;My current gaming setup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full HD Optoma projector - https://www.optomaeurope.com/product-details/hd144x&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NVIDIA Shield TV Pro - https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/shield/shield-tv-pro/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;XBOX controller - https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-wireless-controller/8xn59crbsqgz?cid=msft_web_collection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Extra 4TB HDD for all my movies) - https://www.seagate.com/nl/nl/consumer/backup/expansion-portable/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar 2 - https://store.steampowered.com/app/97000/Solar_2/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rocket League - https://www.rocketleague.com/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Long Dark - https://www.thelongdark.com/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Euro Truck Simulator 2 - https://eurotrucksimulator2.com/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Badland - http://badlandgame.com/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS I have come to despise games with huge initial investment in learning to play them which might contradict my initial point a bit, or maybe reinforce the short feedback argument that I was making…!? I tried Assassin’s Creed today and after 45 minutes I was still seeing the intro of the story, and going through a tutorial. I might not be the audience for those kinds of games as my goal is to just disconnect for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Winning the crown of martyrdom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winning the crown of martyrdom" /><published>2021-02-19T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-19T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom">&lt;p&gt;I had an idea about a zombie plague story where there is no difference between normal people and the infected, except for the lust for brains. They would be more similar to vampires rather than the classic zombies canon, as they would act in a rational and methodical way so that they are not discovered, thus killing in a more serial killer way than a horde of zombies attacking at first sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outlining my story I realized that I have two critical points in my story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does it spread without transforming my zombies straight into vampire? My best idea is to have it in some sort of Coronavirus form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The climax of the story would come at the moment when the zombie population would surpass a critical mass. The amount of brains available for them to eat would shrink under a certain number thus making them go all out without any precaution and also collapsing society as a result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the themes that I wanted to touch on with that second point was the turn in tides in the late Roman Empire when Christians went from being persecuted to being the persecutors in a short time span. The amazing thing that I found when reading the Wikipedia article about this had me completely derailed from my initial idea, because it is a much better story than any zombie book I could ever write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The earliest Christian martyrs, tortured and killed by Roman officials enforcing worship of the gods, won so much fame among their co-religionists that others wished to imitate them to such an extent that a group presented themselves to the governor of Asia, declaring themselves to be Christians, and calling on him to do his duty and put them to death. He executed a few, but as the rest demanded it as well, he responded, exasperated, “You wretches, if you want to die, you have cliffs to leap from and ropes to hang by.” This attitude was sufficiently widespread for Church authorities to begin to distinguish sharply “between solicited martyrdom and the more traditional kind that came as a result of persecution.” [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other mentions of church authorities having to deny martyrdom to those killed after blatant provocation, attacking pagan temples being one example. How has this not been put in a big movie so far, especially with the shift in Hollywood to a more left-atheist orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_02_faithful-unto-death-by-herbert-gustave-schmalz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Herbert Gustave Schmalz - Faithful unto death&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Persecution_of_Christians_in_the_Roman_Empire#Martyrdom&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article on the Persecution of Christians in the Roman Empire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I had an idea about a zombie plague story where there is no difference between normal people and the infected, except for the lust for brains. They would be more similar to vampires rather than the classic zombies canon, as they would act in a rational and methodical way so that they are not discovered, thus killing in a more serial killer way than a horde of zombies attacking at first sight.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Movie theaters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Movie-theaters" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Movie theaters" /><published>2021-02-18T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-18T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Movie%20theaters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Movie-theaters">&lt;p&gt;I am involved in a few communities related to movies. Regardless of the environment, there seems to be a prevailing opinion that movie theaters are the best medium to enjoy movies. We are not talking about the commercial, quick consumer fast-food movies. These are people that are into avantgarde movies, usually found in obscure theaters or only in the Criterion Collection. How far this is from my personal preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visit cinemas as often as your next door neighbor. If a movie like 1917 comes along I would like to enjoy it in a theater as my home system, good as it is, does not come close to the professional systems that you can enjoy for 10€ a movie. The opportunity to go to the movies as a social activity, to watch a bad horror with friends, or the new sequel to a movie you watched together as kid, yeah, count me in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But going to the movies to enjoy a piece of art? Imagine seeing an Ingmar Bergman movie in the cinema, with people constantly pulling out their phones, whispering and popcorn eating? Why would you do that? For these reasons I am absolutely baffled by the cinephiles that think true cinema can only be enjoyed away from home in a crowded or shady cinema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/21_01_empty-movie-theater.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Movie theater picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I am involved in a few communities related to movies. Regardless of the environment, there seems to be a prevailing opinion that movie theaters are the best medium to enjoy movies. We are not talking about the commercial, quick consumer fast-food movies. These are people that are into avantgarde movies, usually found in obscure theaters or only in the Criterion Collection. How far this is from my personal preferences.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gerald’s Game (2017) – 2.5/5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gerald-s-Game-(2017)" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gerald’s Game (2017) – 2.5/5" /><published>2020-09-02T11:19:23+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-02T11:19:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gerald%E2%80%99s-Game-(2017)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gerald-s-Game-(2017)">&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/H3t_DuVHqBQ&quot;&gt;Gerald’s Game&lt;/a&gt; has been entertaining and has kept a bit of suspense until the very end, it is far from being a great movie. A middle aged couple go off for a weekend to try and spice up their marriage only for the husband (Gerald) to have a heart attack while the wife (Jessie) is still tied to the bed and that is where the second act and the weird stuff starts to happen. Weird in a bad way in the case of this movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hallucinations and flashbacks of childhood trauma flood the slowly dehydrating Jessie while she creeps closer and closer to her slow death. Some of the conversations with herself are indeed smartly written and bring a bit of savor to a situation that is inherently static. On the other hand, some of the flashbacks and the realizations that go through the main characters mind are incredibly dull and add nothing to the main story. Without giving away the final twist, which exists although it is not necessary and is there only to make the movie a horror, on top of a thriller and a drama, the handcuffs are a metaphor for the abuse Jessie has sustained from men in her life. While this should come as a surprise to no one, it does not make a lot of sense in the case of her husband, who is not really established as a bad guy, he is just trying hard to spice up the marriage, feed some of his fetishes and save the marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/20_02_geralds-game-bed-picture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bed picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The acting is not terrible and the atmospheric felling of the movie is decent, all in all these characteristic define a passable but forgettable film. For better similar thrillers/dramas with trapped characters I would recommend the superior &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2017038/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1&quot;&gt;All Is Lost (2013)&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1542344/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0&quot;&gt;127 Hours (2010)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="drama" /><category term="horror" /><category term="thriller" /><summary type="html">While Gerald’s Game has been entertaining and has kept a bit of suspense until the very end, it is far from being a great movie. A middle aged couple go off for a weekend to try and spice up their marriage only for the husband (Gerald) to have a heart attack while the wife (Jessie) is still tied to the bed and that is where the second act and the weird stuff starts to happen. Weird in a bad way in the case of this movie.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Le Week-end (2013) – 3.5/5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Le-Week-end-(2013)" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Le Week-end (2013) – 3.5/5" /><published>2020-09-01T11:19:23+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T11:19:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Le-Week-end-(2013)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Le-Week-end-(2013)">&lt;p&gt;This British-French &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/5DkFQKP1FUU&quot;&gt;Le Week-end movie&lt;/a&gt; takes us on a journey in Paris alongside an ageing British couple that try to rekindle their relationship with a weekend getaway in the city of love for their 30th anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning we can see that they view this trip with different eyes, Nick, the philosophy professor wants to please his wife and bring some passion back, while Meg is looking for adventures, either by herself or together if there is no other way. Lead by Meg they wander the streets looking for good food and drink until they find a proper restaurant to enjoy. Along the whole weekend she is not shy to express that this marriage is like a cage for her and the idea of breaking free from it and from the norm of her life and family is something that has had on her mind for a long time. All this happens while Nick admits to being forced to retire from his university and showing his need for the comfort of his family, his wife and their needy adult child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/20_01_le-weekend-paris-picture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Le Weekend Paris picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of an ageing couple that approaches retirement is not new, especially with highly educated upper middle class intellectuals that go through the pains of not having done anything remarkable in the past decades. In this movie it boils down to the different perspectives the main characters have for the future, the wife thinking about breaking out of the cocoon while the husband is looking at making it even more comfortable albeit tighter and with less freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midway during the film, Morgan, an old friend and mentee of Nick’s makes an appearance. Morgan is everything they both lack in their life: charismatic, successful and loved, he seems to be what Nick might have been if life had gone a bit more according to wishes, while Meg loves his spontaneity and adventurous side that does not adhere to most norms, having for example a young pregnant new wife. This character brings the couple to a boiling point but it also is their last hope when they remain without money, thus ending the movie in a metaphor of showing them what they lack and hate in each other but also giving hope to their relationship and to being able to borrow some money for their tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing to complain about the acting, both actors give solid performances and the cinematography is also great, it gives us enough of Paris to get a great European city vibe but it does not go over board in making it the main character of the movie and all this happens with great jazz background music. Although the ending brings a happy feeling to the viewer, I feel it lacked a bit in a more consistent conclusion, the characters being not far off in the ending from the beginning, just with an adventure in their bags and a reassurance of what the relationship really is, and also was for the last 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="drama" /><summary type="html">This British-French Le Week-end movie takes us on a journey in Paris alongside an ageing British couple that try to rekindle their relationship with a weekend getaway in the city of love for their 30th anniversary.</summary></entry></feed>