<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-28T20:58:57+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LavaLens - writing playground</title><subtitle>I have gained an increasing interest in storytelling in recent years. Movies, novels and even poetry fuel my imagination with the potential they have to influence others. No other medium is a close to translating toughts from one person to another as the written word and more recently the moving pictures. I write movie reviews with a focus on European film, short stories and toughts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The plague of tough women in Hollywood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-plague-of-tough-women-in-Hollywood" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The plague of tough women in Hollywood" /><published>2021-02-28T10:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-28T10:11:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-plague-of-tough-women-in-Hollywood</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-plague-of-tough-women-in-Hollywood">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_04-women-statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goddess statue&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a plague of tough unrealistic women in Hollywood. There are countless accounts of women in modern media that are so uni dimensional that the only way they can show strength and independence is by beating up men twice or three times as big as them. This is not realistic and immediately makes me disconnect from a movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to show strength, most of them independent of the sex of the characters and of their size. We do not need to have super hero level powers in every movie out there. Leads do not have to immediately command loyalty or fear from everybody. They do not need to be able to overpower all their enemies and show how tough their are with every action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of film as an art form, and not necessarily as an educational channel. Still, I can think of many examples of strong women and film that can be wonderful examples for young girls and boys, to show them that women can be as tough as men. Ripley from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(franchise)&quot;&gt;Alien franchise&lt;/a&gt; or Clarice Starling from &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.imdb.com/title/tt0102926/&quot;&gt;Silence of the Lambs&lt;/a&gt; incredible leads. You can make anyone strong by showing how they act under pressure. Being able to only show how strong your female character is by beating up men is just bad writing. They need to work to increase their skill, that will earn the respect of the other characters, and of the audience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="movie talk" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some movies just do not have a good story</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Some-movies-just-do-not-have-a-good-story" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some movies just do not have a good story" /><published>2021-02-23T10:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-23T10:11:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Some-movies-just-do-not-have-a-good-story</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Some-movies-just-do-not-have-a-good-story">&lt;p&gt;As I have mentioned multiple times on twitter and here on my blog, I enjoy European film. The fact that the budgets are lower makes the movies made here a lot less dependent on the flashy stuff American films like to throw around like explosions and CGI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, I think it is also important to mention that I am not under the illusion that the European movie market or the European movie writer is in any way better than the North-American one. We do have our masterpieces as do they. What I do want to touch upon is the pretentiousness of depth in European film. Just because the writer was not able to write an interesting story, that does not mean that the elements that exist in the movie are in any way of higher value. No, the absence of a good story is just that, bad writing. It does not heighten the themes and metaphors of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to take a classic example: The Godfather. It introduces a lot of themes, loyalty, tradition, the importance of family and many others. And yet this is all wrapped up in an amazing story that keeps even the people who are not interested in movies glued to the screen. Why is it then that with most low budget movies we sacrifice the story for the sake of a long dull character analysis. There is a really good chance that you will not make a lot of money with your movie, why then throw money and time away on poorly written scripts. At least make art out of it. Throw your character in an amazing adventure, make him act, that will really show his true character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any young writer out there that might read this, please do not get used to writing a boring story and expect the audience to admire your genius of having introduces references to obscure Japanese movies or to unknown soviet writers. Write an amazing story first, create tension, use classic archetypes in which most people will see themselves. If all these are not enough for you, then you can add all the decorative artifacts that will give you satisfaction. But please do not do it the other way around. If all else fails, look at mythology and pick a story from there. It is hard to fail at storytelling if you use stories that have been tested for thousand of years and people still eat them up like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="movie talk" /><summary type="html">As I have mentioned multiple times on twitter and here on my blog, I enjoy European film. The fact that the budgets are lower makes the movies made here a lot less dependent on the flashy stuff American films like to throw around like explosions and CGI.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The long trip to Venus - part I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/The-long-trip-to-Venus" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The long trip to Venus - part I" /><published>2021-02-21T20:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-21T20:11:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-long-trip-to-Venus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/The-long-trip-to-Venus">&lt;p&gt;As a child I always imagined that a trip to Venus would be blinding. Getting closer and closer to the Sun. The thought of having blinds did not occur to me, and maybe it was better that it did not. The real difficulty of such a long trip is the darkness of being alone for such a long time. Four months in a tiny cage is not what you would call a pleasant vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United Space Exploration Organization has banned two people trips. Only the first dozen were made in pairs of scientists. People would get violent all too often. Something about being with another person for such a long time makes you want to kill them. Every word gets on your nerves. Every closed mouth burp makes you lose your mind. That was over 50 years ago, and since then every trip has been made alone or on the rare occasions in groups of five or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am am not the happiest flier in the world. I have degrees in mechanical engineering and I know that failures happen. There is absolutely nothing out there that can save you in that case. Yes, they design for low failure probabilities but that is never close enough to zero to keep me relaxed. As the systems are one hundred percent self driven there is not a lot you can do. The enclosure is also small, sending a big ship on a long trip gets to be expensive. You have enough room for some exercise and basic living. Your limited cubic meters of space serve as bedroom, bathroom, dining hall and gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four months of almost zero communication is not the best for our mental health. Most people catch up on sleep for the first half week. After that we are strongly encouraged to continue with our daily exercises and to keep our minds busy. There is not much room for activities as I previously mentioned, so doing a painting workshop is out of the question. You can do whatever you want with an offline computer. You have all of the knowledge you would want at the tip off your fingertips. Being born in an immensely connected world like Earth makes such a situation difficult. Let me bring up the statistic with the favorite past time activities while on the way to Venus. It seems that TV shows make up a big part of it. Porn, games and reading up on the history and culture of Venus are also enjoyed. I was fed up with the quality of TV shows even while still on Earth. Gaming is not my thing really and I already know the place where I am going. It seems that on top of porn and masturbating, which is also encouraged by the medical staff, I need to find a new pastime activity. Writing might be it. Always wanted to be a writer, I think it is sexy. If I could also smoke I might even enjoy this trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my new activity now picked, I now what will happen next. Every time I try to pick up something new and fun I get bored pretty quickly with it. As soon as I move from the casual writing for fun phase, to the writing as an exercise, I will start to despise it. This should not be a problem in the end, because I only have a couple of alternatives. TV shows is even less appealing and reading is a reasonable one. If I end up on reading every time I get bored with writing then I am in for a pretty fulfilling 4 months ahead. Stay tuned for a lot of stream of consciousness writing in my upcoming texts. I might have to give you more background about this trip in part II.
With my new activity now picked, I now what will happen next. Every time I try to pick up something new and fun I get bored pretty quickly with it. As soon as I move from the casual writing for fun phase, to the writing as an exercise, I will start to despise it. This should not be a problem in the end, because I only have a couple of alternatives. TV shows is even less appealing and reading is a reasonable one. If I end up on reading every time I get bored with writing then I am in for a pretty fulfilling 4 months ahead. Stay tuned for a lot of stream of consciousness writing in my upcoming texts. I might have to give you more background about this trip in part II.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="short story" /><summary type="html">As a child I always imagined that a trip to Venus would be blinding. Getting closer and closer to the Sun. The thought of having blinds did not occur to me, and maybe it was better that it did not. The real difficulty of such a long trip is the darkness of being alone for such a long time. Four months in a tiny cage is not what you would call a pleasant vacation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life gamification</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Life-gamification" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life gamification" /><published>2021-02-20T20:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T20:11:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Life-gamification</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Life-gamification">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_03_gaming-on-mobile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gaming on mobile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never a hardcore gamer. I have played a little chess competitively as a teen and I really enjoyed playing WW2 shooters like Call of Duty 2, and football games like Fifa and Pro Evolution Soccer with friends. In my twenties I also played Football Manager, but I never got into the over night binge gaming negative stereotype that the press likes to throw around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my job has gotten increasingly stressful since Coronavirus started, and the divide between work life and personal time has all but disappeared, I found that I have trouble thinking about something that is not related to my job if I do not find a way to disconnect in a more blunt fashion after my work hours. With gyms still being closed in the Netherlands, I purchased an Nvidia Shield and a game controller to get into gaming again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to tell you that it works. Half an hour of gaming after closing my work laptop has the ability to really disconnect me from the previous 8-10 hours. What I also see in gaming after almost a decade of not playing has made me think the concept of gamification. As humans we are incredibly competitive, as a side effect of evolution. We want to win, we want to prove that we are better than others. Champions are popular and being a champion in your field might, on a primal level, increase your chances of procreating, if I am allowed to bring the discussion to an animalistic instinct level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What games have managed to capture in an incredibly efficient way, is our need to become better, our need to progress and our need to best others. Games are addicting for a reason, it let’s you see the progress you make immediately. We all know that going to the gym is good for us, but as the results cannot be seen in a short feedback loop, it is not as addictive to improve in that way as it is to go from level 4 to level 6 in Rocket League. This short essay has a long introduction but the main point here is the ability of gaming and game related activities to tap into a primal need as human beings. What we need to do now, as a society, is to translate those short feedback loops into real life skills. Games are fun, but gamifying medical school (6 years) or gym results (&amp;gt;1 year) is something that might push us to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-current-gaming-setup&quot;&gt;My current gaming setup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full HD Optoma projector - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.optomaeurope.com/product-details/hd144x&quot;&gt;https://www.optomaeurope.com/product-details/hd144x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NVIDIA Shield TV Pro - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/shield/shield-tv-pro/&quot;&gt;https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/shield/shield-tv-pro/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;XBOX controller - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-wireless-controller/8xn59crbsqgz?cid=msft_web_collection&quot;&gt;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-wireless-controller/8xn59crbsqgz?cid=msft_web_collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Extra 4TB HDD for all my movies) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seagate.com/nl/nl/consumer/backup/expansion-portable/&quot;&gt;https://www.seagate.com/nl/nl/consumer/backup/expansion-portable/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar 2 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/97000/Solar_2/&quot;&gt;https://store.steampowered.com/app/97000/Solar_2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rocket League - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rocketleague.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.rocketleague.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Long Dark - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelongdark.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.thelongdark.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Euro Truck Simulator 2 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://eurotrucksimulator2.com/&quot;&gt;https://eurotrucksimulator2.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Badland - &lt;a href=&quot;http://badlandgame.com/&quot;&gt;http://badlandgame.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS I have come to despise games with huge initial investment in learning to play them which might contradict my initial point a bit, or maybe reinforce the short feedback argument that I was making…!? I tried Assassin’s Creed today and after 45 minutes I was still seeing the intro of the story, and going through a tutorial. I might not be the audience for those kinds of games as my goal is to just disconnect for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Winning the crown of martyrdom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winning the crown of martyrdom" /><published>2021-02-19T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-19T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom">&lt;p&gt;I had an idea about a zombie plague story where there is no difference between normal people and the infected, except for the lust for brains. They would be more similar to vampires rather than the classic zombies canon, as they would act in a rational and methodical way so that they are not discovered, thus killing in a more serial killer way than a horde of zombies attacking at first sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outlining my story I realized that I have two critical points in my story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does it spread without transforming my zombies straight into vampire? My best idea is to have it in some sort of Coronavirus form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The climax of the story would come at the moment when the zombie population would surpass a critical mass. The amount of brains available for them to eat would shrink under a certain number thus making them go all out without any precaution and also collapsing society as a result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the themes that I wanted to touch on with that second point was the turn in tides in the late Roman Empire when Christians went from being persecuted to being the persecutors in a short time span. The amazing thing that I found when reading the Wikipedia article about this had me completely derailed from my initial idea, because it is a much better story than any zombie book I could ever write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The earliest Christian martyrs, tortured and killed by Roman officials enforcing worship of the gods, won so much fame among their co-religionists that others wished to imitate them to such an extent that a group presented themselves to the governor of Asia, declaring themselves to be Christians, and calling on him to do his duty and put them to death. He executed a few, but as the rest demanded it as well, he responded, exasperated, “You wretches, if you want to die, you have cliffs to leap from and ropes to hang by.” This attitude was sufficiently widespread for Church authorities to begin to distinguish sharply “between solicited martyrdom and the more traditional kind that came as a result of persecution.” [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other mentions of church authorities having to deny martyrdom to those killed after blatant provocation, attacking pagan temples being one example. How has this not been put in a big movie so far, especially with the shift in Hollywood to a more left-atheist orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_02_faithful-unto-death-by-herbert-gustave-schmalz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Herbert Gustave Schmalz - Faithful unto death&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Persecution_of_Christians_in_the_Roman_Empire#Martyrdom&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article on the Persecution of Christians in the Roman Empire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I had an idea about a zombie plague story where there is no difference between normal people and the infected, except for the lust for brains. They would be more similar to vampires rather than the classic zombies canon, as they would act in a rational and methodical way so that they are not discovered, thus killing in a more serial killer way than a horde of zombies attacking at first sight.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Movie theaters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Movie-theaters" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Movie theaters" /><published>2021-02-18T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-18T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Movie%20theaters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Movie-theaters">&lt;p&gt;I am involved in a few communities related to movies. Regardless of the environment, there seems to be a prevailing opinion that movie theaters are the best medium to enjoy movies. We are not talking about the commercial, quick consumer fast-food movies. These are people that are into avantgarde movies, usually found in obscure theaters or only in the Criterion Collection. How far this is from my personal preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visit cinemas as often as your next door neighbor. If a movie like 1917 comes along I would like to enjoy it in a theater as my home system, good as it is, does not come close to the professional systems that you can enjoy for 10€ a movie. The opportunity to go to the movies as a social activity, to watch a bad horror with friends, or the new sequel to a movie you watched together as kid, yeah, count me in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But going to the movies to enjoy a piece of art? Imagine seeing an Ingmar Bergman movie in the cinema, with people constantly pulling out their phones, whispering and popcorn eating? Why would you do that? For these reasons I am absolutely baffled by the cinephiles that think true cinema can only be enjoyed away from home in a crowded or shady cinema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/21_01_empty-movie-theater.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Movie theater picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I am involved in a few communities related to movies. Regardless of the environment, there seems to be a prevailing opinion that movie theaters are the best medium to enjoy movies. We are not talking about the commercial, quick consumer fast-food movies. These are people that are into avantgarde movies, usually found in obscure theaters or only in the Criterion Collection. How far this is from my personal preferences.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Instinct (2019) – 2.5/5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/instinct-(2019)" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Instinct (2019) – 2.5/5" /><published>2020-11-23T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-23T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/instinct-(2019)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/instinct-(2019)">&lt;p&gt;Instinct is a Dutch movie which follows a power struggle between an experienced psychologist and a rapist inmate. If you expect a thriller, you might be disappointed as this is more of a female sexual fantasy movie than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carive van Houten is in the main role in a new job at a prison where she has to counsel and asses inmates. There she meets a charismatic inmate (Marwan Kenzari) that seems to be able to manipulate the prison employees, especially the women, into giving him a chance at an unaccompanied probation. While she disagrees with the rest of the prisons psych staff that he should be allowed on probation, she slowly appears to fall under his charm, in part by probably having a chance at fulfilling a bad boy rape fantasy that she seems to have, more than because of his charms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[SPOILERS] I have to give the two main actors credit for doing a good job at creating tension specific for a thriller movie, but in the end I feel that the movie is not a thriller, because of the revenge twist at the end, and is also not a pure drama because of the thriller aspects. It is neither and in the end that does not help the movie out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The antagonist is a convicted rapist that tries to resist his urges, while showing that he has not really changed that much in his 5 years in prison. His main goal is to be released from prison, and not stopping from hurting other people for his personal sexual pleasure. He tries to get a new therapist, in part because he feels that the new one might not give him his parole, but in the end is seduced by her as much as the other way around, leading him to be in the same position at the end of the beginning as he was at the start. Still, a pretty good arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand the female psychologist is obviously not professional as she disregards multiple ethical rules in regards to her work, while actively trying to seduce an inmate she finds attractive to fulfill a sexual fantasy. As the movie progresses this of course backfires, when the inmate turns into an aggressive sexual offender again, but she gets her revenge for something that she actively initiated, which feels incredibly twisted for a movie that tries to end on a high moral note. Do stupid stuff, then just get some revenge and you will be ok kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trailer - &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/0OIetiMoseA&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/0OIetiMoseA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="drama" /><category term="thriller" /><summary type="html">Instinct is a Dutch movie which follows a power struggle between an experienced psychologist and a rapist inmate. If you expect a thriller, you might be disappointed as this is more of a female sexual fantasy movie than anything else.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Dead Don’t Die (2019) – 2.5/5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-dead-dont-die-(2019)" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dead Don’t Die (2019) – 2.5/5" /><published>2020-11-22T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-22T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-dead-dont-die-(2019)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-dead-dont-die-(2019)">&lt;p&gt;The Dead Don’t Die is a zombie deadpan comedy that happens in a small American town. With an ensemble of stars in the film, it falls short off the expectations as the stories of the characters do not really connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the anticipation for this movie was great as more and more stars were added to the list of people that will take part in Jim Jarmusch’s movie. I was certainly excited, expecting an American equivalent to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LIfcaZ4pC-4&quot;&gt;Shaun of the Dead (2004)&lt;/a&gt; or even a new ZomCom on par with &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/8m9EVP8X7N8&quot;&gt;Zombieland (2009)&lt;/a&gt;, but unfortunately it was not. The movie falls short in the story area because of the huge cast and the attempt to give them all air time, but at the end of the movie we see that the arcs are not really interconnected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, there is a big portion of the film spent on a group of what seems to be a trio of runaways from the big city lead by Selena Gomez, that just does not lead to anything or pushes the story forward in any way. And this is not an isolated case, it just keeps going forward with small characters all the way to the end, with no reasonable way to close it all in a satisfying way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the movie does in a pretty good way is the deadpan humor, with dark comedy influences all along the way. We see two small town cops played by Bill Murray and Adam Driver, who just can’t be bothered to panic or turn on their machismo to fight of the zombies. It is just another day at the office for them, which is pretty funny and comes in contrast with Shaun of the Dead, where Shaun tries to save the day to win his girlfriend back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest flaw remains the fact that we follow too many of the characters throughout the movie, which gives the story a very scattered feeling and does help us to connect with any of them. I think the movie might have benefited a lot from a smaller ensemble of stars, which would have led to each of them having more screen time and thus the possibility of of tidying all the smaller stories together. My advice for this one is to skip it if you are not a real comedy zombie movies fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trailer - &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/bs5ZOcU6Bnw&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/bs5ZOcU6Bnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="comedy" /><category term="horror" /><summary type="html">The Dead Don’t Die is a zombie deadpan comedy that happens in a small American town. With an ensemble of stars in the film, it falls short off the expectations as the stories of the characters do not really connect.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Greenland (2020) – 3/5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/greenland-(2020)" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greenland (2020) – 3/5" /><published>2020-11-15T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-15T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/greenland-(2020)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/greenland-(2020)">&lt;p&gt;In this disaster movie we see John Garrity (Gerald Butler) try to bring his estranged wife (Morena Baccarin) and his diabetic soon to safety. The main characters make bad decisions, there are logical black holes all through the movie, but all in all, a slightly bigger budget survival movie in the times of Coronavirus felt appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally like disaster movies, and my enjoyment of this one might be a bit more pronounced than for the general public. I could see mediocre writing all throughout the movie, and I will also admit that at some point I was hoping for the hysterical wife to die, just to make the movie better, but unfortunately that did not happen and we got a happy ending. One of the more obvious plot holes is the fact that society had already fallen into panic, but they still somehow managed to drive hundreds of miles, which would require them to refuel multiple times along the way, especially with those huge Americans cars that eat up gasoline like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[SPOILERS] The movie has a side plot of the husband trying to rekindle the relationship, which I think was totally unnecessary, as the anxiety of the world being destroyed is enough to keep the viewers entertained, having to worry about them not getting back together seems to only tame the main concern of survival. But like all good Hollywood movies they seem to be happy together by the third act and also on the way to live another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of technical achievement there is nothing wrong with the movie. Acting could have been better, but then again, this is not the kind of movie that goes for nominations for best acting. My personal preference is to see the dark human transformation from regular person to complete animal that would do everything for survival. That theme is touched on in this movie but could have been developed a lot more, instead of the stale we broke up and I immediately slept with someone else scene they decided to put in. In the end, the main achievement of the film is to give us a distraction from Coronavirus for 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trailer - &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/1AyxdYP1SNc&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/1AyxdYP1SNc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="action" /><category term="thriller" /><summary type="html">In this disaster movie we see John Garrity (Gerald Butler) try to bring his estranged wife (Morena Baccarin) and his diabetic soon to safety. The main characters make bad decisions, there are logical black holes all through the movie, but all in all, a slightly bigger budget survival movie in the times of Coronavirus felt appropriate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vengeful 7 (2020) – 1.5/5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vengeful-7-(2020)" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vengeful 7 (2020) – 1.5/5" /><published>2020-11-08T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-08T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vengeful-7-(2020)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vengeful-7-(2020)">&lt;p&gt;Vengeful 7 or 7 Wrekers in its original Dutch title is a 2020 movie by Tristan van Doorn. If you guessed it is a Tarantino &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/nIOmotayDMY&quot;&gt;Hateful Eight (2015)&lt;/a&gt; copy taking place in the Netherlands in WWII, but at a much lower quality, then you have guessed right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As all the action takes place in a single room, and the image keeps getting out of focus during the film, my guess is that the movie was filmed on basically no budget and a tight schedule. Tristan van Doorn, the writer, director, producer, cameraman and so on, usually does shorts under his own independent film company named Doorn Eden Films. From what I could find this is his first feature length film, and indeed you can see that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The acting is pretty bad, the set is minimalist, everything taking place in one room and you can see the influence of The Hateful Eight at every turn, that is to be gentle and not call it a ripoff. With a story that has a lot of twists we see the resistance fighters against the Nazis, which is a really abused subject in Dutch movies. A couple of higher quality alternatives would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/7APEb3ngkpk&quot;&gt;Black Book (Zwartboek 2006)&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/xyUeBQf4dP8&quot;&gt;Riphagen (2016)&lt;/a&gt; if the subject is interesting to the readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case particular film, the limit between amateur film and professional film is really hard to distinguish. As the man behind this movie is still young, I hope that this was a learning experience for him, but at this moment in time, Vengeful 7 was more of a comedy in how bad it was than a real war drama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trailer - &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/NzvT1VKSMW0&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/NzvT1VKSMW0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="drama" /><category term="war" /><category term="suspense" /><summary type="html">Vengeful 7 or 7 Wrekers in its original Dutch title is a 2020 movie by Tristan van Doorn. If you guessed it is a Tarantino Hateful Eight (2015) copy taking place in the Netherlands in WWII, but at a much lower quality, then you have guessed right.</summary></entry></feed>