<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-18T20:12:02+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LavaLens - writing playground</title><subtitle>I have gained an increasing interest in storytelling in recent years. Movies, novels and even poetry fuel my imagination with the potential they have to influence others. No other medium is a close to translating toughts from one person to another as the written word and more recently the moving pictures. I write movie reviews with a focus on European film, short stories and toughts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Quit your job</title><link href="/quit-your-job" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quit your job" /><published>2021-04-18T11:11:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T11:11:00+02:00</updated><id>/quit-your-job</id><content type="html" xml:base="/quit-your-job">&lt;p&gt;There is a common desire among my friends, a dream to stop working. A dream to be independent, to not have a job. Less money would be ok as long as we would not have to do something that we do not want for 40 50 60 hours every week. Not many try to do something about this. The closest most might get to this is to start a business. You might end up working even more than before, but at least you gain a lot of independence. That also depends on how you see it. You change your boss for your customers, and a secure paycheck for extra stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many youtube channels showing how life can be lived on the road or in a remote cabin. There are also farmers who to this day live as farmers have always lived, dependent on the land, dependent on the weather, but other than that, they seem to be freer than the regular office worker. You would have to get you hands dirty to be a farmer. The same way Neo gave up a cushy life for the true life in the Matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, exchanging one job for another, which I also might hate, like farming, does not sound like such a great deal. My big independence dream ticket was always some kind of financial independence and living from the interested of my saving or better said from the dividends my investments might make on the stock market. Another option would be working in a creative field of some kind. Writing, podcasting, voice acting? I have been exploring these dreams for years now. I just bought a microphone and I play with it. Like with everything in life, it seemed easy but it is not. If it was, everybody would be living in the south of Italy doing 2 or 3 hours of voice acting a day while enjoying life for the rest of the day. Podcasting is a field that has a lot of money at the top, and zero money for the rest. It is just not there. Youtube videos are just as complicated as podcasting with the extra difficulty of handling video editing as well as audio editing. And writing? Oh we all love writing. Writing movies, writing plays, writing books and writing speeches. All can be incredibly satisfying but your best bet is to be some kind of copy writer for some corporate websites. Still sounds better than an office job. You could do that job from anywhere. You don’t even need a good internet connection to upload text. Doesn’t even sound that stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why even have these desires?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a shop in Eindhoven selling puzzles, board games and such. There are not many customers in that shop. The owner is also the only employee. He sits around the shop all day, watches youtube, posting in online forums related to puzzles and boardgames. He generally just delves into what seems to be his passion. Does he make a fortune out of it? Surely not. Is it a glamorous career? Not really. Is it stressful? Probably, as rents are expensive and online retailers are killing all the small shop. But the real question is if he is happy doing it? He is, he looks like a little child when he talks about his passion. He breathes boardgames, he plays them all the time, he knows everything he can about them and can’t wait for the boardgames conventions around Europe. Not even this situation seals the deal for me. I know myself, if I follow my biggest passion and focus on that like this store owner, I will get bored of them and start hating everything related to it after a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, what are we really looking for? What does that independence really mean? Is it financial and stress related or is it the time that we can use for ourselves? Would a person that does not need to work and has full financial freedom for the rest of his life still do something productive, but that would be more important to him than his previous job? Human rights activism instead of an office clerk job? Or is our desire hard coded in our genes and sleeping like a cat in the sun is the dream that we are searching for?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="short story" /><summary type="html">There is a common desire among my friends, a dream to stop working. A dream to be independent, to not have a job. Less money would be ok as long as we would not have to do something that we do not want for 40 50 60 hours every week. Not many try to do something about this. The closest most might get to this is to start a business. You might end up working even more than before, but at least you gain a lot of independence. That also depends on how you see it. You change your boss for your customers, and a secure paycheck for extra stress.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Drinks for the poor</title><link href="/drinks-for-the-poor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drinks for the poor" /><published>2021-03-12T10:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-12T10:11:00+01:00</updated><id>/drinks-for-the-poor</id><content type="html" xml:base="/drinks-for-the-poor">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_07-drinks-for-the-poor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drunk on the street&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I come from a poor country. In poor European countries drinking is seen as an escape from the daily struggles of life. It is also seen as an integral part of every of every major event in life. You drink when your child is born. You drink at weddings and you drink at funerals. You drink if you favorite team wins the match but you also drink if you lose your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation always appeared to me as typical for a person that hates life. It is tough, you don’t have enough money to escape your situation so alcohol becomes an escape. It never solves any problems but it gives you a few hours of escape from the abyss that is a poor life. I always saw alcoholism as a consequence of poverty and lack of education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What surprised me is the presence of alcoholism in rich countries. I live in the Netherlands now, one of the richest countries in the world. There is a strong social safety net here. Yes you pay high taxes but if you lose your job the states takes care of you. I could have never imagined that the drinking to drown my sorrows could exists in such a country. Here you can escape poverty. Why drink then. I am not talking about the functional alcoholic that somehow got into a bad divorce and is struggling with alcoholism now. I am talking about trailer living, teeth missing alcoholic as a way of life person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also reading trough some of Charles Bukoswki’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Notes_of_a_Dirty_Old_Man&quot;&gt;Notes of a Dirty Old Man&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah, that kind of drunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That kind of alcoholism is a way of life. It is an escapism form of some kind. The way I escape from my reality by watching shitty zombie TV shows, some other person drinks. Is the regular alcoholism treatment even an option for them? I used to be a heavy drinker. I was not the expensive wine or whiskey type of guy. I was the buy the cheapest beer at Lidl drinker. Spending every free hour drinking. Similar in that regards to many depressed drinkers, that seem to always end in suicide.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="short story" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Death Row</title><link href="/death-row" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Death Row" /><published>2021-03-11T10:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-11T10:11:00+01:00</updated><id>/death-row</id><content type="html" xml:base="/death-row">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_06-hangman.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hangman knot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being on death row means you have a lot of time to think. You think about what your life means. You think about what you could do on the outside. I was sentenced a decade ago. There are no doubts about my conviction, I am guilty. I know it and the justice system knows it. What I do not know is how I managed to kill someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I am honest with myself and with you reader, I think I even thought that it would be cool to be a killer. A predator. People would be afraid of me, what can be cooler than that? What you do not know is that being cool but on death row has absolutely no benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have time in here. Nothing but time. You can do some workouts in your cell, walk around when they take you outside. Another thing that I thought about before my crime was that sitting in a cell and reading books might be a lot more relaxing than having a job and being stressed. What I did not know is that my situation is never going out of your mind. Even if they cancel my executing for some reason, and there is a big chance for that, I will still live all my life in a cell. No work stress, no vacation and no family. I will be forever in a cell. Nothing can change that. Knowing this is the real punishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Correction facilities should correct the behavior of the inmates. It should be an unpleasant experience that will prevent them from repeating their actions after they are released. In my case and in the case of others on death row there is no release. We are here to prevent us from going out in society again. We are here as an example of what happens if we do not adhere to societies rules. It is all understandable, I don’t think the system is all that bad. If I had taken a different path in life, I would probably still support life in prison and executions. What I am interested in now are the effects this has on the human mind. Yes, we have done horrible things. Yes we are a danger to society and should be used as examples. On the other hand keeping a person looked up until they eventually die, by old age, execution or suicide seems to defeat the purpose of them being alive. What is the point?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was there at any point in time in the past a person on death row that still did something meaningful with his life? Wrote a good poem. Played incredible correspondence chess? Or is it just torture until an eventual death?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="short story" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy Doomsday</title><link href="/happy-doomsday" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy Doomsday" /><published>2021-03-02T10:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-02T10:11:00+01:00</updated><id>/happy-doomsday</id><content type="html" xml:base="/happy-doomsday">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_05-fire-wood.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fire wood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not been stressed in months. I feel at ease with myself. Working the field for a few weeks a year and gathering fire wood are my only concerns. The zombies are slow, you just need to crush their heads if you come in contact with them. Otherwise I do not have any worry in the world. There is no power struggle in our community as we are all heavily armed. If there is an attempt to gain power and somehow use the rest as slave workers, that would quickly end in death for one team. In that regard we are closer in organization to an anarchist commune from before the end of the world, just with lots of weapons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remembering how many nights I had struggled to fall asleep because I did not finished a report for work, it all seems like a bad dream. How could I have that much in my life at that point, all the comforts that only kings had for centuries and still fell so unhappy? Here I am reading, napping every day. I play the guitar for at least an hour every evening, something that I always wanted to do but never did. I do need to work in the field so that we can have fresh food for the future, but that only takes less than two or three hours a day. Even if all my crops go to waste for a reason or another, I can still make some scavenging trips and get enough food to live for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there might come a time when the modern wonders of medicine will be missed, but right now, as I am in good health, that seems like a far away possibility maybe decades in the future. At that point you can see life as coming to it’s natural end. It can happen before, but if seven billion dead has thought us something, it is that we should enjoy life when we can, and when the end comes let it come. Nothing to be sad about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep coming back to my initial idea of the differences in life quality between now and three years ago. I was eating bad food, because I always found stress to be the perfect excuse for a bad diet. Balding, getting fat. I had a gym membership to make myself feel good but I never went. Shitty Netflix shows to dumb the mind after twelve hours at the office, mortgage payments, social engagements where you do not want to be. I hated even having to call my parents. If I knew that I can exchange all the stress of a modern office job for a bit of manual labor and shitting in a hole in the ground in a wooden closet, I would have taken the later any day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="short story" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The plague of tough women in Hollywood</title><link href="/the-plague-of-tough-women-in-Hollywood" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The plague of tough women in Hollywood" /><published>2021-02-28T10:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-28T10:11:00+01:00</updated><id>/the-plague-of-tough-women-in-Hollywood</id><content type="html" xml:base="/the-plague-of-tough-women-in-Hollywood">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_04-women-statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goddess statue&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a plague of tough unrealistic women in Hollywood. There are countless accounts of women in modern media that are so uni dimensional that the only way they can show strength and independence is by beating up men twice or three times as big as them. This is not realistic and immediately makes me disconnect from a movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to show strength, most of them independent of the sex of the characters and of their size. We do not need to have super hero level powers in every movie out there. Leads do not have to immediately command loyalty or fear from everybody. They do not need to be able to overpower all their enemies and show how tough their are with every action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of film as an art form, and not necessarily as an educational channel. Still, I can think of many examples of strong women and film that can be wonderful examples for young girls and boys, to show them that women can be as tough as men. Ripley from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(franchise)&quot;&gt;Alien franchise&lt;/a&gt; or Clarice Starling from &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.imdb.com/title/tt0102926/&quot;&gt;Silence of the Lambs&lt;/a&gt; are incredible leads. You can make anyone strong by showing how they act under pressure. Being able to only show how strong your female character is by beating up men is just bad writing. They need to work to increase their skill, that will earn the respect of the other characters, and of the audience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="movie talk" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some movies just do not have a good story</title><link href="/Some-movies-just-do-not-have-a-good-story" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some movies just do not have a good story" /><published>2021-02-23T10:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-23T10:11:00+01:00</updated><id>/Some-movies-just-do-not-have-a-good-story</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Some-movies-just-do-not-have-a-good-story">&lt;p&gt;As I have mentioned multiple times on twitter and here on my blog, I enjoy European film. The fact that the budgets are lower makes the movies made here a lot less dependent on the flashy stuff American films like to throw around like explosions and CGI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, I think it is also important to mention that I am not under the illusion that the European movie market or the European movie writer is in any way better than the North-American one. We do have our masterpieces as do they. What I do want to touch upon is the pretentiousness of depth in European film. Just because the writer was not able to write an interesting story, that does not mean that the elements that exist in the movie are in any way of higher value. No, the absence of a good story is just that, bad writing. It does not heighten the themes and metaphors of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to take a classic example: The Godfather. It introduces a lot of themes, loyalty, tradition, the importance of family and many others. And yet this is all wrapped up in an amazing story that keeps even the people who are not interested in movies glued to the screen. Why is it then that with most low budget movies we sacrifice the story for the sake of a long dull character analysis. There is a really good chance that you will not make a lot of money with your movie, why then throw money and time away on poorly written scripts. At least make art out of it. Throw your character in an amazing adventure, make him act, that will really show his true character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any young writer out there that might read this, please do not get used to writing a boring story and expect the audience to admire your genius of having introduces references to obscure Japanese movies or to unknown soviet writers. Write an amazing story first, create tension, use classic archetypes in which most people will see themselves. If all these are not enough for you, then you can add all the decorative artifacts that will give you satisfaction. But please do not do it the other way around. If all else fails, look at mythology and pick a story from there. It is hard to fail at storytelling if you use stories that have been tested for thousand of years and people still eat them up like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="movie talk" /><summary type="html">As I have mentioned multiple times on twitter and here on my blog, I enjoy European film. The fact that the budgets are lower makes the movies made here a lot less dependent on the flashy stuff American films like to throw around like explosions and CGI.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The long trip to Venus - part I</title><link href="/The-long-trip-to-Venus" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The long trip to Venus - part I" /><published>2021-02-21T20:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-21T20:11:00+01:00</updated><id>/The-long-trip-to-Venus</id><content type="html" xml:base="/The-long-trip-to-Venus">&lt;p&gt;As a child I always imagined that a trip to Venus would be blinding. Getting closer and closer to the Sun. The thought of having blinds did not occur to me, and maybe it was better that it did not. The real difficulty of such a long trip is the darkness of being alone for such a long time. Four months in a tiny cage is not what you would call a pleasant vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United Space Exploration Organization has banned two people trips. Only the first dozen were made in pairs of scientists. People would get violent all too often. Something about being with another person for such a long time makes you want to kill them. Every word gets on your nerves. Every closed mouth burp makes you lose your mind. That was over 50 years ago, and since then every trip has been made alone or on the rare occasions in groups of five or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am am not the happiest flier in the world. I have degrees in mechanical engineering and I know that failures happen. There is absolutely nothing out there that can save you in that case. Yes, they design for low failure probabilities but that is never close enough to zero to keep me relaxed. As the systems are one hundred percent self driven there is not a lot you can do. The enclosure is also small, sending a big ship on a long trip gets to be expensive. You have enough room for some exercise and basic living. Your limited cubic meters of space serve as bedroom, bathroom, dining hall and gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four months of almost zero communication is not the best for our mental health. Most people catch up on sleep for the first half week. After that we are strongly encouraged to continue with our daily exercises and to keep our minds busy. There is not much room for activities as I previously mentioned, so doing a painting workshop is out of the question. You can do whatever you want with an offline computer. You have all of the knowledge you would want at the tip off your fingertips. Being born in an immensely connected world like Earth makes such a situation difficult. Let me bring up the statistic with the favorite past time activities while on the way to Venus. It seems that TV shows make up a big part of it. Porn, games and reading up on the history and culture of Venus are also enjoyed. I was fed up with the quality of TV shows even while still on Earth. Gaming is not my thing really and I already know the place where I am going. It seems that on top of porn and masturbating, which is also encouraged by the medical staff, I need to find a new pastime activity. Writing might be it. Always wanted to be a writer, I think it is sexy. If I could also smoke I might even enjoy this trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my new activity now picked, I now what will happen next. Every time I try to pick up something new and fun I get bored pretty quickly with it. As soon as I move from the casual writing for fun phase, to the writing as an exercise, I will start to despise it. This should not be a problem in the end, because I only have a couple of alternatives. TV shows is even less appealing and reading is a reasonable one. If I end up on reading every time I get bored with writing then I am in for a pretty fulfilling 4 months ahead. Stay tuned for a lot of stream of consciousness writing in my upcoming texts. I might have to give you more background about this trip in part II.
With my new activity now picked, I now what will happen next. Every time I try to pick up something new and fun I get bored pretty quickly with it. As soon as I move from the casual writing for fun phase, to the writing as an exercise, I will start to despise it. This should not be a problem in the end, because I only have a couple of alternatives. TV shows is even less appealing and reading is a reasonable one. If I end up on reading every time I get bored with writing then I am in for a pretty fulfilling 4 months ahead. Stay tuned for a lot of stream of consciousness writing in my upcoming texts. I might have to give you more background about this trip in part II.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="short story" /><summary type="html">As a child I always imagined that a trip to Venus would be blinding. Getting closer and closer to the Sun. The thought of having blinds did not occur to me, and maybe it was better that it did not. The real difficulty of such a long trip is the darkness of being alone for such a long time. Four months in a tiny cage is not what you would call a pleasant vacation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life gamification</title><link href="/Life-gamification" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life gamification" /><published>2021-02-20T20:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T20:11:00+01:00</updated><id>/Life-gamification</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Life-gamification">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_03_gaming-on-mobile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gaming on mobile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never a hardcore gamer. I have played a little chess competitively as a teen and I really enjoyed playing WW2 shooters like Call of Duty 2, and football games like Fifa and Pro Evolution Soccer with friends. In my twenties I also played Football Manager, but I never got into the over night binge gaming negative stereotype that the press likes to throw around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my job has gotten increasingly stressful since Coronavirus started, and the divide between work life and personal time has all but disappeared, I found that I have trouble thinking about something that is not related to my job if I do not find a way to disconnect in a more blunt fashion after my work hours. With gyms still being closed in the Netherlands, I purchased an Nvidia Shield and a game controller to get into gaming again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to tell you that it works. Half an hour of gaming after closing my work laptop has the ability to really disconnect me from the previous 8-10 hours. What I also see in gaming after almost a decade of not playing has made me think the concept of gamification. As humans we are incredibly competitive, as a side effect of evolution. We want to win, we want to prove that we are better than others. Champions are popular and being a champion in your field might, on a primal level, increase your chances of procreating, if I am allowed to bring the discussion to an animalistic instinct level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What games have managed to capture in an incredibly efficient way, is our need to become better, our need to progress and our need to best others. Games are addicting for a reason, it let’s you see the progress you make immediately. We all know that going to the gym is good for us, but as the results cannot be seen in a short feedback loop, it is not as addictive to improve in that way as it is to go from level 4 to level 6 in Rocket League. This short essay has a long introduction but the main point here is the ability of gaming and game related activities to tap into a primal need as human beings. What we need to do now, as a society, is to translate those short feedback loops into real life skills. Games are fun, but gamifying medical school (6 years) or gym results (&amp;gt;1 year) is something that might push us to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-current-gaming-setup&quot;&gt;My current gaming setup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full HD Optoma projector - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.optomaeurope.com/product-details/hd144x&quot;&gt;https://www.optomaeurope.com/product-details/hd144x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NVIDIA Shield TV Pro - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/shield/shield-tv-pro/&quot;&gt;https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/shield/shield-tv-pro/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;XBOX controller - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-wireless-controller/8xn59crbsqgz?cid=msft_web_collection&quot;&gt;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/xbox-wireless-controller/8xn59crbsqgz?cid=msft_web_collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Extra 4TB HDD for all my movies) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seagate.com/nl/nl/consumer/backup/expansion-portable/&quot;&gt;https://www.seagate.com/nl/nl/consumer/backup/expansion-portable/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar 2 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/97000/Solar_2/&quot;&gt;https://store.steampowered.com/app/97000/Solar_2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rocket League - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rocketleague.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.rocketleague.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Long Dark - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelongdark.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.thelongdark.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Euro Truck Simulator 2 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://eurotrucksimulator2.com/&quot;&gt;https://eurotrucksimulator2.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Badland - &lt;a href=&quot;http://badlandgame.com/&quot;&gt;http://badlandgame.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS I have come to despise games with huge initial investment in learning to play them which might contradict my initial point a bit, or maybe reinforce the short feedback argument that I was making…!? I tried Assassin’s Creed today and after 45 minutes I was still seeing the intro of the story, and going through a tutorial. I might not be the audience for those kinds of games as my goal is to just disconnect for 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Winning the crown of martyrdom</title><link href="/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winning the crown of martyrdom" /><published>2021-02-19T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-19T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Winning-the-crown-of-martyrdom">&lt;p&gt;I had an idea about a zombie plague story where there is no difference between normal people and the infected, except for the lust for brains. They would be more similar to vampires rather than the classic zombies canon, as they would act in a rational and methodical way so that they are not discovered, thus killing in a more serial killer way than a horde of zombies attacking at first sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outlining my story I realized that I have two critical points in my story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does it spread without transforming my zombies straight into vampire? My best idea is to have it in some sort of Coronavirus form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The climax of the story would come at the moment when the zombie population would surpass a critical mass. The amount of brains available for them to eat would shrink under a certain number thus making them go all out without any precaution and also collapsing society as a result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the themes that I wanted to touch on with that second point was the turn in tides in the late Roman Empire when Christians went from being persecuted to being the persecutors in a short time span. The amazing thing that I found when reading the Wikipedia article about this had me completely derailed from my initial idea, because it is a much better story than any zombie book I could ever write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The earliest Christian martyrs, tortured and killed by Roman officials enforcing worship of the gods, won so much fame among their co-religionists that others wished to imitate them to such an extent that a group presented themselves to the governor of Asia, declaring themselves to be Christians, and calling on him to do his duty and put them to death. He executed a few, but as the rest demanded it as well, he responded, exasperated, “You wretches, if you want to die, you have cliffs to leap from and ropes to hang by.” This attitude was sufficiently widespread for Church authorities to begin to distinguish sharply “between solicited martyrdom and the more traditional kind that came as a result of persecution.” [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other mentions of church authorities having to deny martyrdom to those killed after blatant provocation, attacking pagan temples being one example. How has this not been put in a big movie so far, especially with the shift in Hollywood to a more left-atheist orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/21_02_faithful-unto-death-by-herbert-gustave-schmalz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Herbert Gustave Schmalz - Faithful unto death&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Persecution_of_Christians_in_the_Roman_Empire#Martyrdom&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article on the Persecution of Christians in the Roman Empire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I had an idea about a zombie plague story where there is no difference between normal people and the infected, except for the lust for brains. They would be more similar to vampires rather than the classic zombies canon, as they would act in a rational and methodical way so that they are not discovered, thus killing in a more serial killer way than a horde of zombies attacking at first sight.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Movie theaters</title><link href="/Movie-theaters" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Movie theaters" /><published>2021-02-18T10:19:23+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-18T10:19:23+01:00</updated><id>/Movie%20theaters</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Movie-theaters">&lt;p&gt;I am involved in a few communities related to movies. Regardless of the environment, there seems to be a prevailing opinion that movie theaters are the best medium to enjoy movies. We are not talking about the commercial, quick consumer fast-food movies. These are people that are into avantgarde movies, usually found in obscure theaters or only in the Criterion Collection. How far this is from my personal preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visit cinemas as often as your next door neighbor. If a movie like 1917 comes along I would like to enjoy it in a theater as my home system, good as it is, does not come close to the professional systems that you can enjoy for 10€ a movie. The opportunity to go to the movies as a social activity, to watch a bad horror with friends, or the new sequel to a movie you watched together as kid, yeah, count me in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But going to the movies to enjoy a piece of art? Imagine seeing an Ingmar Bergman movie in the cinema, with people constantly pulling out their phones, whispering and popcorn eating? Why would you do that? For these reasons I am absolutely baffled by the cinephiles that think true cinema can only be enjoyed away from home in a crowded or shady cinema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/21_01_empty-movie-theater.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Movie theater picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">I am involved in a few communities related to movies. Regardless of the environment, there seems to be a prevailing opinion that movie theaters are the best medium to enjoy movies. We are not talking about the commercial, quick consumer fast-food movies. These are people that are into avantgarde movies, usually found in obscure theaters or only in the Criterion Collection. How far this is from my personal preferences.</summary></entry></feed>